<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Jimspiration</title>
  <subtitle>A personal website</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://joclarke.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-07-20T15:30:54.000Z</updated>
  <id>http://joclarke.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Jim Clarke</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Value Add</title>
    <link href="http://joclarke.github.io/2016/07/19/Value-Add/"/>
    <id>http://joclarke.github.io/2016/07/19/Value-Add/</id>
    <published>2016-07-19T15:18:43.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-07-20T15:30:54.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;The-Value-Add-Challenge&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#The-Value-Add-Challenge&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;The Value Add Challenge&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Value Add Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a final part of our training for startup jobs, we were tasked with coming up with a project to add value to our city or Venture for America itself. I’ve seen some great projects in the works, efforts designed to strengthen our communities, focus on truly revitalizing our cities, little things that may in fact leave the world better than we found it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking long and hard about what I’d like to do, something tangible and longterm that reflects the things I really care about in life, especially as they relate to VFA, the things that get me up in the morning. Something that could possibly orient people toward each other. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Family-Dinners&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Family-Dinners&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Family Dinners&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Family Dinners&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Family has always been one of the most important things in my life. Like, probably top three. Coming from a big Italian family, two tenets were enforced from an early age– family is not restricted to blood and nothing unites family like food. I’d like to bring these two pillars of my sense of family to Philly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is by no means exclusive. Each week, I’d like to have five or six different people over for a dinner to spend time together. They will not all be affiliated with VFA– I want to bring all the communities I find in the city together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My office is in the southernmost section of the city, so on Fridays I’ll take the long way home and pass through the Italian section, pick up some ingredients, and get dinner going for everyone that evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;The-Accelerator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#The-Accelerator&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;The Accelerator&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Accelerator&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A second piece of this project will be my involvement with the VFA Accelerator. Sergei has begun to take me on as a mentee, and I’ve talked to him about volunteering my time and work to the Accelerator. While I have no idea whether or not I’ll start a company, I think the Accelerator is an incredible resource and if I’m not building something at very least I want to be empowering others to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h2 id=&quot;The-Value-Add-Challenge&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#The-Value-Add-Challenge&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;The Value Add Challenge&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Value Add Cha
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Philadelphia, Venture for America, side project, entrepreneurship" scheme="http://joclarke.github.io/tags/Philadelphia-Venture-for-America-side-project-entrepreneurship/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Training Camp: The Final Week</title>
    <link href="http://joclarke.github.io/2016/07/19/Training-Camp-The-Final-Week/"/>
    <id>http://joclarke.github.io/2016/07/19/Training-Camp-The-Final-Week/</id>
    <published>2016-07-19T14:44:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-07-20T18:18:46.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, we’re rolling into the final week at Training Camp 2016. It’s been a wild, transformative, exhausting two weeks. I’ve learned so much, grown so much, and seen so many new sides of myself I think it’s going to take several weeks to process it all. I leave Providence in four days, so I thought I’d post a short update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Goals&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Goals&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Goals&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ll take a second now to briefly reflect on the goals I made before arriving, a status report of sorts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To be on a first-name basis with every Fellow.&lt;br&gt;I’m almost there on this one, which is quite an accomplishment for someone as bad with names as I am. I think if I do a little social media stalking later, I’ll have everyone down!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To identify and explore new affinities for different aspects of the startup world.&lt;br&gt;I’ve definitely got some great interest areas to explore both on the side and at work once I get out to Philly. I’m really stoked on human-centered design and good UX/UI practices, which seem to go hand-in-hand due to their focus on the user. Being in a product-centered role, I think I can explore these thoroughly in my job. I’d also like to take a class through the American Graphics Institute to study UX/UI a little more.&lt;br&gt;I’ve also discovered an attraction to data analysis and the insights it carries. I want to learn a little more about it on my own time by learning SQL and Python and taking on small data challenges through (Kaggle.com)[www.kaggle.com].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To grow as a leader.&lt;br&gt;Maybe I’ve achieved this one in a roundabout way. I never project managed in a challenge or lead a discussion. I’m not sure I made an impact at all, really. But I stayed true to the things I value, those basic truths to which I cling. I’ve learned even more that there’s so much I don’t know and that I’m so bad at having certain conversations. I’ve met amazing people and seen so much hope and hard work even in the midst of uncertainty and difficulty and struggle. Love has been proven to me again and again. And I’m happy with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To love others well.&lt;br&gt;Always a struggle, forever learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Three-Things&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Three-Things&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Three Things&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Three Things&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, we had a talk from Melissa Withers about life at a startup. In the talk, she suggested we pick three things to work on over the next two years, so I’d like to take a moment to talk through that. I want to invest time furthering something I’m good at, developing something I love, and learning something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Better my relationships&lt;br&gt;I love community, I love people, I love relationships. Building and maintaining these relationships has been a skill I’ve been privileged enough to cultivate over the years, and I want to invest time continuing that, especially with regard to mentoring relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Invest in reading and writing&lt;br&gt;Lifegiving activities. I haven’t been able to practice them as much as I’d like in the recent years, and I’d love to grow in these areas in this next chapter, especially since they relate to my longterm goal of teaching. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn to build physical things&lt;br&gt;Hayden and I want to build things together. I want to play with Raspberry PIs, code them, analyze them. I want to woodwork and use tools and put real things into the world. This is a passion of mine, and a big part of life that I think is essential for me to learn. These are skills I can pass on to kids and mentees or whatever. They can build my home, even. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Final-Note&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Final-Note&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Final Note&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Final Note&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before I end this update, I want to lay something out. This website is about a person– me. It’s self indulgent, a catalogue of things I’ve learned, both necessary and extraneous. It’s a way for me to sort through what I think is vital to my life at different times. One day, maybe it will be a record. If you find this, know that I’m being candid because we learn from each others’ lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If my life and projects, good and bad, teach something and help someone create something good that wasn’t there before, I’ve succeeded. We’re here to lift people up, to shrink so community can grow. I hope you find that in this record. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Well, we’re rolling into the final week at Training Camp 2016. It’s been a wild, transformative, exhausting two weeks. I’ve learned so mu
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Philly Action Plan</title>
    <link href="http://joclarke.github.io/2016/06/24/Philly-Action-Plan/"/>
    <id>http://joclarke.github.io/2016/06/24/Philly-Action-Plan/</id>
    <published>2016-06-25T00:44:26.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-06-27T03:34:16.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;I-didn’t-see-it-coming…&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#I-didn’t-see-it-coming…&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;I didn’t see it coming…&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I didn’t see it coming…&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;But it happened! I’m committed to work at LUXTECH, LLC in Philadelphia, PA. As a grown and groomed Southern boy, this will be a significant shift from the Georgia, Tennessee, Virginia locales I’ve inhabited over the last 22.5 years. As the move looms, I want to start thinking about what I can do in my first 3 - 6 months to make the city my home and my home a better place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Action-Plan&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Action-Plan&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Action Plan&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Action Plan&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;Work&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Work&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Work&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Work&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I plan on going in as equipped as possible to succeed in Technical Sales. This means sucking the marrow out of training camp, and doing as much research as I can into LEDs and the industry on the side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I want to suss out a solid understanding of what a sustainable effort level will look like. I want to go in strong and stay strong– avoid burnout. This means figuring out what long-term healthy effort will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Along with (2), I’d like to establish a healthy routine before I even leave camp– going to bed on time, waking up early to exercise, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Work on a side project related to work but not directly. Probably skills development, like UX/UI design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;City&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#City&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;City&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;City&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I want to be constantly investing in the communities that Philly will bring with it. This includes the other Fellows headed that way, finding a good church, a good jiu-jitsu gym, etc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will look into volunteer opportunities as soon as possible. I’ve always wanted to be a volunteer firefighter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Find my coffee shop. Get a dog. Have someone over for dinner minimum once a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h2 id=&quot;I-didn’t-see-it-coming…&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#I-didn’t-see-it-coming…&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;I didn’t see it coming…&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I didn’t see it c
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Venture for America Goals</title>
    <link href="http://joclarke.github.io/2016/06/23/Venture-for-America-Goals/"/>
    <id>http://joclarke.github.io/2016/06/23/Venture-for-America-Goals/</id>
    <published>2016-06-24T02:53:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-06-25T00:24:07.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;Venture-for-America&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Venture-for-America&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Venture for America&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Venture for America&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am apart of (Venture for America)[ventureforamerica.org], an entrepreneurship fellowship for recent graduates and nonprofit. Venture’s goals are threefold– to offer Fellows hands-on entrepreneurship experience, to grow startup companies around the US, and to revitalize American cities through the growth of these companies and companies the Fellows will eventually go on to found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Training-Camp&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Training-Camp&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Training Camp&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Training Camp&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m currently at training camp in Providence, RI, a five week program in which we study, compete, and collaborate to learn the skills necessary to plunge into work at the startups that have hired us this fall. These are skills span the spectrum in terms of “hard” and “soft,” from coding to adopting an internal locus of control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to take the opportunity now to outline my general goals for the remainder of training camp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Goals&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Goals&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Goals&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To be on a first-name basis with every Fellow.&lt;br&gt;I want to come away with a few deep relationships and friendships, but it would be a shame to miss out on any of the Fellows and their stories. We have some amazing people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To identify and explore new affinities for different aspects of the startup world.&lt;br&gt;I’m coming in to training camp with very little business experience. I hope to come away from camp not only educated in key functions of startups and their employees, but with new interests or even passions that I can explore on the side which may or may not be related to my role in Technical Sales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To grow as a leader.&lt;br&gt;I’ve never thought of myself as a leader of a particular sort. Yes, I’ve found myself in leadership roles at various times in my life, but more by accident than intent. In the past week, I’ve not only found myself surrounded by leaders, but have begun (for the first time) to recognize myself as one.&lt;br&gt;What sort of leader will I be? How can I shape that vision? I think it’s a combination of stating my hopes and allowing my experiences over the next five weeks to constantly inform the working out of those hopes, so here we go:&lt;br&gt;I often have a vision for a project. I hope to communicate that vision and adhere to it.&lt;br&gt;I value community. I hope to promote the flourishing of the relationships within my team and around it.&lt;br&gt;I hope to serve others.&lt;br&gt;I hope to uplift those around me.&lt;br&gt;I hope to stay humble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To love others well.&lt;br&gt;Self explanatory. Always the nucleus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h2 id=&quot;Venture-for-America&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Venture-for-America&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Venture for America&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Venture for America&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I 
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
